TIMOTHY WON

MOBILE: (240) 888-3131 • TKW21189@GMAIL.COM • MeetTimWon.herokuapp.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Top-performing consultant with over three years of professional experience within the Public Sector, working extensively with government startup agencies and maintaining a professional focus on information & data management, project management, and business process improvement. Mr. Won currently resides in PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) Public Sector Financial Services consulting practice and is a Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM).

CORE COMPETENCIES

Information & Data Management
Waterfall/Agile Methodologies
Business Intelligence

Data Analysis
Application Design
Leadership & Coaching

Business Process Improvement
Business Development

Contract Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

PricewaterhouseCoopers LLC

Advisory Senior Associate

July 2013 - Present Washington, DC

- Leads data warehousing efforts for a start-up financial regulatory agency to extract, transform, and load (ETL) data from its cloud-based case-management system, supporting creation and delivery of the physical server architecture as well as development of a custom-coded Python software orchestrating data migrations
- Leads analysis of current and future-state information needs for an operational business-arm by conducting interviews and developing data collection methodologies to understand data demand gaps
- Re-designed a department's case review system utilizing SQL and VBA to improve the data collection process, identify top-performing candidates, and support feedback mechanisms for a team of 40+ employees
- Managed the compliance of a \$22bn stimulus program by performing independent data forensics, surveillance, and risk services. Parsed monthly fund-manager transactional data with SQL procedures to ensure adherence to program rules and assessing potentially suspicious patterns of behavior for a major public-private investment fund
- Led a project Management Office (PMO) delivering a cohesive, client-facing view of \$20+ mm account team over a dozen contracting vehicles, development custom workflow tools and supporting the growth of junior associates
- Supports business development efforts by leading pricing strategies and competitive analysis for major federal financial institutions and services

PricewaterhouseCoopers LLC

Advisory Associate

Aug. 2011 – June 2013 *Washington, DC*

- Conducted analysis on budgetary data on regions across to identify areas of ineffective cost management. Used findings to standardized costs across regions and presented recommendations to cut excess costs
- Assessed their database for internal control reviews across its portfolio of offices and programs, assessing gaps, overlaps, and areas of improvement to meet Federal Managers Financial Integrity Act (FMFIA) regulations
- Conducted internal control assessment including third-party reliance reviews for a \$700bn investment fund. Created Summary, Planning and Results (SP&Rs) documentation; designed and executed test plans; tested controls and documented findings in Summary of Aggregated Deficiency logs

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science, Information Systems

Robert H. School of Business: University of Maryland: College Park

Aug. 2007 – June 2011 College Park, MD

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, VBA, Ruby (introductory)

Software/Tools: Microsoft Excel/Powerpoint (advanced), SQL Server, Postgres, Github